What's
the last 24 Well, really 12 hours been
like for you? Yeah, no, the the last
couple of you know, 12 hours has been
it's been surreal, man. You know,
hearing my name called. Uh
I was feeling emotions I I never felt
before, man. Overflowing joy. So, uh
it's been great, you know, hanging out
with my, you know, agency, uh Texas Tech
staff, and you know, my friends, family,
and everything. So, it's been great.
>> How many text messages have you gotten
in the last throughout that time?
>> I've got a lot, man. I did I I don't
have my notifications on. So, I
I got asked that yesterday, but um I had
a yeah, good amount. I'm still replying
to a lot of them. Um so, You said
yesterday limited
interaction with Aaron Glenn, but now
that you've been here and everything
like that, what are the conversations
been like? Uh I I haven't met with them.
Yeah, I haven't met with them today,
yeah. I mean, I seen him for a I seen
him uh a little bit in the weight room,
introduced myself, but uh I haven't had
a like a formal meeting with him yet.
One of the things um analysts had last
night being that the treaty guys is that
y'all came from winning programs, where
you guys were winning a lot last year.
I know you weren't at Tech long, but you
guys kind of turned things around there
last year. Do you feel like you learned
something there that you can bring here
cuz this team is trying to to turn it
around? Yeah, 100%, man. I mean,
uh you know,
the reason that we had the success we
had at Tech was So, you know, a lot a
lot more than me, man. It's just a whole
bunch of things. It was, you know,
McGuire and it was the staff and it was
the alumni and the, you know, players
that we acquired acquired. So, um you
know, I I
but I learned for myself like at least
uh what's important for success is, you
know, creating a a great routine, you
know, effective routine, and staying
consistent to that routine. So, I'm
looking to carry um carry on the same
thing on my pro career. Um you know,
just creating a even better routine uh
to you know, help me become a better
player. So, Did you get to meet Frank
Reich when he was coming in through that
transition and you were leaving
Stanford? Was there any Yeah, I actually
Yeah, I met Reich um so, prior to my pro
day, uh the Jets I had a dinner with
them and Reich was actually there. And I
was sitting there and I was looking at
him a little funny and I was like, "Man,
you look familiar. You familiar?" And
then he was like, "Yeah, like
I was I was coaching at Stanford with
with Luck." Um and you know, he talked
to me and he talked about a couple
players like Sam Roach and everything.
We chopped it up. Um but you know, we
both had to be said the same thing about
Stanford is a great great uh great spot
with great players. From um you know,
it's an amazing campus and great
university as a whole. So, David, did
you get to know Arvell at all throughout
this process or do you have a history
with him? You know, you
you guys were sort of
wanted to to one of the only few of the
sports at the position and Yeah.
Yeah, no. My my uh communication or
contact with him was like limited. Uh
you know, it's just say, "What's up?" Um
you know, "Good luck." and what what
not. But yeah, it was limited.
And after your three years Oh, sorry. I
was going to say you guys sort of listed
as the same position, but you play you
play different positions. Is that how
you would put it?
>> Yeah, I would Yeah, I would say that,
yeah.
After your three years at Stanford,
did you reach out to the league
sometimes to get advice or reborn on
where you might go in the draft if
you're thinking of coming out?
As far as
where did you think you were going to go
if you did come out compared to going
second overall? Obviously, things worked
out so well for you.
>> Yeah, I I bro, I
honestly didn't think at all of leaving
after Stanford. I mean, I had one more
year and I had put, you know, I had a
graded pretty high on my PFF, but you
know, I didn't put anything on tape that
I was like extremely proud of. So, I
didn't really think of leaving after
three years, but um
I want to say like fourth round. I
really don't know, to be honest. I know
a couple of my my teammates were asking
me why I didn't leave, but you know, I
just felt like I needed another year.
What did you feel like you improved on
doing that year at Tech? Yeah, I mean, I
feel like I improved on
my understanding of the game, you know,
as a whole, my football IQ. Um and then
obviously my pass rushing ability, too.
You know, getting under Coach Ayu was
was great because, you know, he's super
knowledgeable about pass rushing and he,
you know, he took my game to the next
level. And that was like the first time
I could really rely on the on my coach
for, you know, pass rushing um
techniques that, you know, I could that
transferred over to the game. So, Were
there edge rushers or best rushers that
you studied or watched, whether it be in
pros or in college? Yeah, for sure. I
watched a lot of um watched a lot of Von
Miller. Um you know, that that that was
probably the first uh professional
player that I started watching. And you
know, I I watched him a little bit
freshman year. Um
not really too intense, like not
studying his film, just a little
something. Uh but I think it's after
that sophomore year is when I started
like really honing in on him. Um you
know, I'd watch his, you know, his his
highlights. Uh I'd create like cut-ups
on my phone. And you know, whenever I
was doing like extra work over on the
weekends, you know, I'd get on the tire
guy and try to like emulate, you know,
his moves and stuff like that. So, you
know, I watched a lot of Von. Um I don't
know I got my like pass rush uh stance,
you know, that three-point stance
get-off from Aidan Hutchinson, you know,
he has an elite get-off.
Um
So, yeah, those are the two main ones.
And then um yeah, I just go on
Instagram, man. And Instagram's got a
lot of like, you know, D-line page,
D-line guru. I got a lot of cut-ups
that, you know, I I sometimes save into
a folder. And then if I see something
that I like that I can, you know, I
think I could, you know, maybe translate
to the game, I'll I'll do it. Save it.
When did you know that this was a
possibility that the pros were something
that, you know, you could be
not maybe not a a first-round draft
pick, but a professional football
player?
Yeah, um I'd probably say
I'd probably say I started really going
after it um my sophomore year um of of
college. Um you know, I had a I didn't
really have a great season. Um and you
know, I wasn't happy with my success or
you know, the team's success. So, um
that's when I kind of turned things
around.
Um my approach to the game completely
changed. Um
My attitude towards, you know, rehab and
um extra work and film study completely
changed.
Uh it did a complete 180. So,
um yeah.
Was there anything in particular that
that really helped
flip that switch? Like did anybody
influence you with that?
>> No, I really just the disappointment
that I felt like in my in myself and
just the disappointment I felt like in
the in the team. Um
it just kind of like yeah, that was
probably the main motivating factor.
>> brother was your brother played at
Harvard?
>> Yes, sir. Did you come to this part of
the country a lot to watch him play?
Most of the Ivy League schools are in
the
East. Did you What was that experience
like? Yeah, no. I never actually
saw a game in person. Um we would watch
like the games um we would watch like
the games online sometimes. Um but yeah,
I never seen
saw his game in person. Um but you know,
I came out for his graduation.
Um
but yeah.
What was his influence on you?
Obviously, you you're a good student,
too. And he's obviously very good
student going to Harvard.
>> Yeah.
His influence on you? Oh, his influence
on me? Oh, oh, I mean, just his his
approach to to academics, man. I mean,
you know, generally speaking like the
the general notion of like football
players is, you know, they just don't
take academics seriously. It's kind of
all football. But you know, he was able
to balance both football and and school
and be elite at both of them. So,
I felt like I had that same ability to
do so. So, How important was it to get
your degree from Stanford before moving
on to Texas Tech and obviously now the
NFL? Yeah, it was extremely important.
And then um you know, I was uncertain in
how long I it would take to get it, but
uh you know, I really I didn't know I
was going to graduate early till after
freshman year. So, um you know, after
freshman year I got I I knew it was a
possibility. I knew I wanted something
better for my football career. Um which
which entailed me transferring. So, you
know, I got all my academic uh Shout out
TJ Brunette. But you know, he helped me
taking like summer classes and extra
curriculums and whatnot um in order to
help me graduate. So, you know, it was
extremely important getting in there and
then finishing what I started. So, Is
there any
Is there any quarterback in the NFL that
you're particularly looking forward to
sacking? Yeah, Bryce Young if I ever get
the chance.
You guys, are you still close? And are
you guys close? Yeah, yeah, actually um
I mean, not close just cuz, you know,
there's like a little bit of an age age
gap. But um you know, where I train at
right now uh for my pass rushing back
home is at Golden West College. And I
don't know if y'all know, but like a lot
of the quarterbacks uh train down there.
Um you know, Bryce Young and you know,
Noah Fifita.
Uh so, like a lot of elite quarterbacks
over there. So, I actually just saw him
probably like two weeks ago. Uh he
chopped it up, gave me some advice, you
know what I'm saying? So,
Now that it's water under the bridge,
the whole thing where you didn't come
here for the meeting, Yeah. What were
What were your emotions after that? Did
you think maybe they're not going to
pick me or did you kind of know all
along the the meeting thing was
overrated? Um
Initially, I probably thought like yeah,
they're not they're not going to uh pick
me. But then also I was thinking back um
to the interactions that I had with
them, you know, prior to that
to the meeting getting canceled. And I
was thinking back to the interaction I
had with them at the combine and at the
steakhouse and the FaceTimes and moves.
You know, I was like, you know, this is
we had a good relationship with them.
Like, you know, I felt I felt good
talking to them. I felt like they had a
good attitude towards me and vice versa.
So, um
So, yeah, no. I I really after that uh
after they canceled it and you know, I
got with my my agent and he was like,
you know, don't think too much about it,
you know. Uh you know, just trust the
process, trust what they're doing.
Um and just stay consistent, man. So,
yeah. When you faced Washington when you
faced Oregon in the playoffs, what do
you remember about Sedeeq, who's in your
in your teammate? Oh, yeah, I remember.
Um I remember there was a lot of game
planning against him. I remember
he was probably
I think we we we identified him as the
best like offensive player, to be
honest, besides quarterback. Uh but
yeah, I think we identified him as like
the best uh offensive player.
Um
you know, he's extremely fast. Uh he's a
good great size on him for a tight end.
Um so, yeah.
What's the last like 36 hours been like
for you? Yeah, um obviously this has
been a lot of travel, obviously. Um, a
lot of changing moving pieces, but it's
been good. Um, getting out to really uh
New York for the first time, kind of
Jersey, you know, get see what
everything's really about, get to meet
people. It's been great.
You probably just talked about being
versatile and also like being, you know,
attacking in the run game. Where did all
that come from?
>> Yeah. Um, it's really just I think just
being an undersized tight end a little
bit, to be honest. Um, not being a
liability on, you know, first and second
down.
Uh, you know, being able to do a little
bit, cuz it also helps the team out,
too, and it helps myself out. It's it's
rare you see a
a pass-catching tight end that also
really likes to get, you know, kind of
dirty with the blocking. Yeah. Where
does that come from? Is that I mean, is
that aggressiveness? Is that violence?
Did you find it back in high school? Was
it an escape to get the football? And
where where did that aspect of your game
come from? Yeah, I mean, you kind of
touched on a little bit of all those
pieces. You know, I think one I've kind
of always had it. Um, I think it's been
just how I think the game should be
played, you know, kind of like love,
aggression, passion, all those things,
but um, regardless, it really just comes
down to how much I love the game, you
know, what I'm willing to do for
teammates and things like that. What
made you think when the Jets called you
that it was a prank? Did Did the phone
number not register? Or what did you
even No, no. I was just
That was just like my biggest fear. Uh,
if you go like what like it was like
Shidor and like all that stuff that
happened with him. It's just like that
just like it'd be such a
it's such a moment full of so many
emotions, you know, it'd be kind of a
you know, not a fun way to you get a
prank call, stuff like that. But no,
obviously, um, the call and everything
was amazing. And you got You got to come
from a small town in Idaho. I mean, what
what does it mean to be representing
that? I I can't imagine a lot of guys
have made it to the NFL from there.
Yeah, yeah, not too many.
Um, but no, it's awesome. Like you said,
you get to represent something a bit
bigger than yourself, so um, it means
something to those people back home, and
especially all the people that have, you
know, helped me get to this point. It's
awesome. Did you realize right away like
when Darren Waller called you that
it wasn't a prank?
When did you say, "Okay, I'm safe."
Yeah. Um, I mean, it was really just
when I started talking to each
individual coach, you know, and
management, those things. So, um, but
no, once I really it kind of hit me, you
know, this isn't a prank call, so this
is the real deal, and you I was super
excited.
Did you always play tight end? Uh, no,
no, no. I played like like small ball. I
was like running back. Um, and then once
I got to high school, it was uh
receiver, and then college to tight end.
How did you How did you make that move?
Like why why did they make that move
with you? Yeah. Um, obviously, I think
it's just kind of where they saw my body
kind of transitioning to, but also I
think another way to kind of separate
myself from, you know, the other tight
ends. Not that I could have done that at
receiver, but I just think tight end
kind of fits me better as a person.
Frank Reich was pretty excited on that
call based on the video we saw. Like
what what's been your interaction with
him, you know, throughout
[clears throat] this process? Yeah. Um,
we really only did like about one Zoom
meeting with him, and you know, we just
kind of got to know each other, and then
they kind of, you know, talked
provisions they had, you know, with the
tight end room, including myself, you
know, those things. So, but no, they're
You could definitely tell they're great
people to be around him and Alfredo, so
I'm excited.
What were some of your favorite tight
ends to watch kind of in the NFL? Yeah.
Um, obviously, George Kittle. Uh, George
Kittle's probably my favorite tight end
to watch. I like watching Kyle Rudolph
check a lot. They do a really good job
over there.
Um, obviously, like like Kolsen
Loveland, uh, you know, those guys that
have also come from Idaho, which is
pretty crazy.
Um, the Kyle Pitts does a lot of a lot
of great things. Um, Evan Engram, so my
I got a lot of comp, too, so I've
watched a lot of Evan Engram. Um, I
really try to watch everyone. I've
watched Mason Taylor, you know, I've
watched Jeremy. I've watched both those
guys, and they both do a really good
job. What
for you, you know, last year was, you
know, your first time getting
significant playing time at Oregon, so
you had to like kind of bide your time.
Like what what was what kind of
challenge was that for you? Obviously,
coming try to prove yourself, and then
get your chance. I mean, you had a lot
of very quick turnaround. But like what
what what was that journey like for you
having to bide your time at Oregon?
Yeah. Um, obviously, it went by really
fast, but you know, I wouldn't change
anything, you know, obviously, I got to
sit behind some great players like
Terrance Brooks and then Patrick
Herbert, and learn from them, and then
obviously, last year kind of take the
reins of the offense. And I mean, it was
great, um, you know, getting to help
young guys out, but also kind of
showcase my abilities in, you know, in
the pass-catching game and the in the
run game. So, you know, it
I was reading like you did You did
workout plans for people.
How did that come about? Yeah. Um, I've
always just like loved working out in
the gym.
Um, so, you know, I've
she was already really in high school.
Um, you know, I'd start working out and
stuff, and I'd always have like friends
and stuff reach out and be like, "Hey,
can you make me a plan?" So, I started
making them plans and stuff like that,
and then it's something I kind of love
doing. You we kind of live in a day and
age in college football now where
a player isn't playing, they leave, and
they go somewhere where they aren't
playing. You sat, you learned, you
developed, and then when you got your
chance, you you shined. I mean, what
what made you want to stay? What made
you not want to leave? Um, I mean, it
was really I definitely like
contemplated it at the time, you know,
it's super easy to do that, but I just
got I kind of found it more rewarding.
Um, I kind of tried to, you know, beat
him out for his spot, and
um, one, it made us closer, and two, I
think it made me a lot better. Um, you
know, kind of made me focus on what I
needed to improve on, you know,
weaknesses in my game, and you know,
kind of see what he was better at than I
was. And um, no, I think it was good um,
mindset-wise, uh, maturity-wise, but
also development-wise.
How much did
playing at Oregon, especially against
the talented players that are also
currently in the NFL, also help you get
to this point? Yeah, I mean, you kind of
said it. It's just like the experience
of playing against high-level players, I
think is huge. You know, at those big
schools like Oregon, Ohio State, you
know, all those schools, you get a a
good, you know, sample size of what's
going to be like the competition piece.
Obviously, it's a lot different at this
level, but you do get like a sample
size. How much did it help you running
in the draft process, running 4-3-9,
having the 43.5-in vertical? Where do
you think you might have gone before
that, and did it move you up the boards,
you think?
Um, I think it definitely helped a
little bit. I mean, not anything crazy.
You know, I think people knew I was
fast, and people knew I could jump. It
was just kind of putting the
measurables, you know, on paper, you
know, so people could kind of see what
they were working with. But um, no, I
definitely think it helped me a little
bit, you know, it was nice. I don't
think people
thought I was as fast as I was. Um,
obviously, so kind of getting to prove
that was good. What What was your
impression of Adetomiwa Adebawore? I
know you went against him Yeah. at
Indiana. Yeah, obviously, um, I think
that's a great pick. Um, I think he's
the best corner I played against all
year, uh, for sure. But no, I mean, he's
a bit you can say on the undersized
side, too, but um, no, it definitely
doesn't show it on the field, you know,
one thing I love about his game is how
much
you know, passion and you know, speed he
plays with. So, you know, it's awesome
to get a team up with him and, you know,
Cooper as well. Played against both of
them twice, so um, no, they're great
guys.
What do you have to do? Uh, are you
still 241? Is that your weight? Uh, no,
I'll be I'll I'll play this season at
like 245 to 247.
So, as a blocker, when you're when
you're not 260, what do you have to do
to compensate for that? Yeah. Um,
obviously, in my game, it's kind of huge
pad level um, and speed to contact, cuz
obviously, I'm not um, as tall as some
of those guys or as big as some of those
guys. It's using, you know, my little
things that I have, whether that's pad
leverage or you know, speed to contact.
Everybody good? Thank you, everyone.
Just describe what these last uh
12, 16 hours have been like.
Uh, it's been just a really good
uh fun time, uh exciting. It was very
anxious at first, but uh just when I got
the call, it was just a very exciting
time and just fun time and a relief of
stress. You said last night when 16
passed, you didn't think you'd
be here. Yes, sir.
>> What what what happened after that for
you? What were you thinking? And and
when did you actually find out? Uh, I
actually found out uh I mean, what I was
thinking, I mean, just maybe somebody
else is going possibly get me. Uh,
but I found out once they called me. I
didn't even know they traded back up
until I got the call, and uh coach
Ulbrich, I mean,
Darren Ulbrich told me that they traded
up, uh and that's kind of when I figured
out. Why did you want to be there so
bad?
I mean, just the the city and state of
New York, um,
just a really good atmosphere. The
coaching staff that that Aaron Glenn has
brought out here, uh just really good
people
uh that love football, love ball, and
have a great game a great plan. Um, and
I've just I wanted to be a part of that.
Do you know much about the offensive
personnel here like Geno Smith and
Garrett Wilson and so forth, your new
teammates? Uh, yes, I know about a few
of them,
um, and I've watched them in the past,
of course. With that Garrett Wilson, I
mean, played at the state, a
high-profile school as well.
Uh, yeah, I actually grew up a Ohio
State Buckeyes fan, so um, I was
actually a fan of him when I was
younger.
What um, you touched on this a little
bit last night, but what do you think
you can take from the lesson at IU of
turning things around there
Uh, I mean, I would just say like the
mindset the mindset that I
was instilled into me,
um, and then just trying to bring others
along,
um, and also just creating a
relationship with trying to with
everybody in the locker room. I feel
like that kind of helped us be
successful, cuz we were out there
playing for each other as well. So. You
said you were a fan of Garrett, and I'm
guessing you know Adonai from his time
with the Colts, too, right?
>> Yes, sir. How do you see yourself
fitting in with that group, and when do
you think that group will be good?
Um, I am not sure yet. Um, that's really
for the coaches. I haven't We haven't
had that conversation yet, um, and so
I'm looking forward to see what they
say, but I feel like that is a really
good group of receivers, um, and we
could do something special, but I mean,
it ain't going to be given to us. We got
to go out there and prove it and earn it
every single day. So,
uh that'll be really exciting just to be
a part of that group. What was it What
was it you liked about Garrett's game?
Uh, I mean, really everything. Uh, just
he was has some really good releases, a
really good route runner, and attacked
the ball really good really well in
college, especially.
Um, and just how um, aggressive he
played. That was something that I really
found
found uh enjoyable. How's it sunk in yet
that
you're going to be teammates? Uh, no,
not yet.
The Jets posted video of the call a few
last night and
Aaron Glenn was referencing being in his
office
in his message. Did you feel like a
bond there or did you feel like it
seemed like he referenced a pretty
powerful conversation you guys Uh, yeah,
the conversation that we had in his
office felt like we just connected
really well and
just everything that he was talking
about I really I really enjoyed what I
was hearing and really loved what I was
hearing and I told him I mean that's
something that I would love to be a part
of and so the fact that he actually came
and got me I was grateful. And then Sean
Jefferson seemed pretty excited.
>> Oh, yeah.
What are your impressions been of him so
far?
Uh, I mean just everything like you said
his energy he has some really high
energy love how he is just
not aggressive but I just like that
and then he's going he's going to be
hard on you he's going to tell you what
you need to hear and not what you want
to hear and I just that's the that's
type of coach that I I want to be
coached by
and so I'm looking forward to it. What
what's the last few months been like
going from winning the national [snorts]
championship to coach rule?
Uh, it's been really busy
you go straight into training from that
championship for combine and pro day and
then you go visit so I had a lot of
visits so
it's just been very busy a little
overwhelming but at same time it's been
a good time just being able to be a part
of something like that
and it's a dream come true so I've been
very grateful for the opportunities I've
been given.
>> How many 30 visits did you do? I did 12.
Wow. Yes, sir.
Omar about 3 hours down the road here at
Penn State
you had that play
that will be one of the greatest plays
in college history. How much do you
think that play you had a good resume
anyway do you think that even enhanced
your resume even more with the pros? Uh,
I would say yeah I mean that's kind of I
feel like that's kind of what got my
name really known
I feel like just that play they started
really seeing who I was
and started watching me a little bit
more after that.
You were a fan of Garrett but was there
somebody you patterned
some of your skills after like was there
somebody you really watched when you
were a younger? Um, when I was really
younger Julio Jones
but obviously
definitely not the same type of player
but this past season I I liked watching
Jamar Chase Davante Adams and Amon-Ra
St. Brown a lot.
As it was there anything that was said
about you during the pre-draft process
you know you hear all the mock drafts in
the media reports and stuff that you
felt was wrong as was inaccurate or any
criticisms of your game that you thought
were wrong?
Uh, I mean no I mean if somebody feels
like that then I mean I loved hearing it
cuz I feel like that that means I still
got something to work on and improve
and so I feel like that just helps me
become a better player and so I like
hearing that type stuff
cuz it always pushes me to get better.
What do you feel like you improved on
the most while you were at Indiana?
Uh,
I would say just my mentality and
mindset. Um, I feel like that changed
tremendously throughout my career. Um,
and it just allowed me to be more free
when I'm playing. Take a couple more.
Obviously that talked for months it
seems like it's been forever that
Fernando was going to go number [snorts]
one but as a former teammate now and
just kind of knowing how he developed
and got to that point what was that like
seeing him go number one? Uh, I mean
kind of like you said we all knew it was
coming but I mean I was just very
excited for him I mean he really
deserves it
just real genuine hard working
dude and a really good friend
and I just I'm excited to see what he
has for his career he's going to be a
great player. Omar one of the first
things Aaron said was your toughness and
your your your fearlessness. What in
your life has maybe shaped those two
traits for you? Uh, I would say
really my relationship with Christ
that's kind of what really shaped it
coming across that my sophomore year
just going through things that's really
what kind of made me tough and fearless
cuz I know that at the end of the day he
he is the one who has a plan and
everything's going to go according to it
and so just trusting in him and then I
would obviously say
Uh,
I'll probably go my parents just they
were both athletes in college and so
they've been through what I've been
where I was at and so just how they
raised me growing up and raised my
sisters and me
was they always made sure they pushed us
and never let us get lackadaisical or
complacent so
What were you hearing after your junior
year as far did you reach out to the
advisory board in the league to find out
what round you might go in and
how much did you help yourself this past
year you think? Uh, no I didn't I didn't
really have any
plans or idea of going after my junior
year
so I didn't really ask but what really
helped me going into this past year was
my just the conversations I had with my
offensive coordinator. Um, he just
really
told me straight out what I needed to do
or what I could do to get to this point
and so he really said it was up to me
and what I did and also I would say my
teammate Elijah Sherrod we all he always
pushed me to be a better player we
pushed each other and held each other
accountable and that's kind of what got
me here to this point.